Muhammad Samiullah

Software Engineer

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With over 4+ years of adeptness in full stack development, spanning React, Typescript, and JavaScript for dynamic apps, SQL for data orchestration, and HTML5 along with CSS3 for crafting immersive interfaces. I love to be a software developer rather than a language-dependent developer. I enjoy what I do, and it reflects in my work!

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer | Tkxel

August 2023 - Present, Lahore, Pakistan

- Revamped Contact module for Real Estate Dashboard, achieving an impressive 50% speed increase with enhanced UI/UX, which contributed to 15% overall growth of the company.
- Integrated complete frontend solution for a US based client with APIs that resulted in 50% speed optimization and 40% higher user retention.
- Spearheaded Jest and Vitest test suites that upshot 75% faster testing and 25% more code coverage for the app.
- Succeeded software development lifecycle by implementing agile methodologies, resulting in a 40% increase in team efficiency and delivering projects 20% ahead of schedule.

Senior Frontend Engineer | Emerald Labs

July 2022 - April 2023, Lahore, Pakistan

- Oversaw design and development of 3 highly interactive web apps: 15% user retention increase with a 30% annual revenue spike. Optimized code structure and quality: 30% bug reduction, 70% code maintainability.
- Engineered fully responsive and cross-device compatible UI/UX design for dashboards, health & fintech apps: 25% user interaction boost.
- Communicated with junior devs in designing and developing of a cutting-edge E-Health platform, from integrating payment gateways to optimizing page load times: 35% rise in company sales.
- Outperformed sophisticated tax calculator app for multiple monthly users, and managed full-cycle design tasks within client guidelines.

Senior Software Engineer | LAAM

July 2020 - June 2022, Lahore, Pakistan

- Applied D3.js chart visualization to cut the analysis time by 50% for the Analytics team, driving a 15% sales increase.
- Implemented UI/UX strategy, achieving a 40% user participation boost and a 25% bounce rate reduction.
- Evaluated tech debt prioritization, and managed legacy codebase refactoring for 30% less maintenance, 50% app performance boost.
- Coordinated with C-level executives and departments to drive a substantial increase in profits, averaging 2M+ daily sales in just 2 years.
- Completed DevOps practices, A/B testing for sales and homepage features, resulting in a 7.5% boost in conversions.
- Mentored software engineers, contributing to overall success with effective communication and team strategy and much more.

Software Engineer | Sucsel

June 2019 - June 2020, Lahore, Pakistan

- Tailored UI/UX strategies for central e-commerce, driving a 20% visitor activity increase, and a 15% platform sales boost in 6 months.
- Promoted CMS UI by elevating SEO performance, and boosting organic search tra c by 15%, while deploying 7 Shopify E-commerce stores, contributing to a whopping 200% revenue surge.
- Earned lean tech development for high-quality software systems, exceeding client expectations while spearheading initiatives with renowned brands like Ali Xeeshan, MNR, HSY, Hussain Rehar, and Tena-Durrani.

Software Engineer | Her Ground

April 2018 - April 2019, Lahore, Pakistan

- Analyzed & deployed a customized Shopify store, achieving 45% faster speed, and 30% less cart abandonment.
- Examined code reviews, providing valuable feedback, and maintaining high coding standards.
- Forecasted expertise in responsive front-end development (JS, HTML5, CSS3), ensuring seamless user experience.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science with a major in Computer Science (BSCS) | FCCU, A Chartered University

Lahore-Pakistan, 2019

SKILLS

Languages: Typescript, JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML5, CSS3

Integrations: Docker, Continuous Integration (CI), REST API, Eslint, Prettier

Tools & Platforms: Git, Postman, VS Code, Slack, Jira, Figma

Databases: PostgreSQL, Firebase, NoSQL, MongoDB

Development Methods: Scrum, Agile, Kanban

Design Techniques: Product Development, Atomic Design, Design Patterns

Testing: Jest, Vitest, Puppeteer, Cypress

Libraries & Frameworks: ReactJs, Chakra UI, Ant Design, Redux, Zustand, Tailwind, Styled Components, React Testing

Library, Storybook, Tanstack, AWS Amplify, AWS Lambda, AWS SES, AWS SNS, Technical SEO, Shopify

Interest & Strengths: Al Enthusiast, Communication, Management and Leadership, Product Development, Global

Entrepreneurship, Web Design, Growth.

Language: English Professional (C1)